残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で
運命さえまだ知らない 痛いけな瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて飛達
ほとばしる熱いパックスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
神話になれ
オープンに悩む
The unit one's awakened and been set free.
Zele sure won't stay quiet about this, will they?
This is insane.
The EVA series aren't capable of generating S2 organs themselves,
but we never imagined that one would be able to take one into itself this way.
This incident is at extreme odds with the scenario we created.
Gando Ikari.
It was a mistake to entrust nerve to him, wasn't it?
Hmm.
But he was the only one who could achieve this project's goals.
Ikari, what's going on in your mind?
It's begun at last.
Indeed, this is the beginning.
The damage the EVA incurred is beyond the Hendlick limit.
Yes.
It may be a while before we can restore everything to normal.
Fortunately, the Magi system can be transferred to a new location.
We may be able to begin working as early as tomorrow.
This place isn't going to be viable anymore.
It's just a matter of time before they decide to abandon it.
Mm-hmm.
Most likely.
But for the time being, we'll have to use the secondary control center.
Without the Magi?
Yes.
We'll clean the dust off and be back in business by this afternoon.
But the chairs are too cramped down there, and the sensors don't operate smoothly.
It's difficult to work there.
Well, at least the layout is the same as our original control center.
At least we have an alternative.
We have no choice when it comes to using Unit 1.
It may be restrained by the cage, but are you sure it's safe?
Well, no heat emissions, free electrons, electromagnetic fields, or chemical reactions, and the S2 unit's completely inactive.
Nevertheless, on three separate occasions, Unit 1 has moved without power.
You can't judge this situation by just the things you can see.
Uh-huh.
We sure can't take any chances, that's a fact.
It's as unpredictable as you are, Major.
Uh, sorry.
However, our concerns are not limited to Unit 1.
Correct.
Serious damage was sustained by Unit 0 and 2.
Headquarters was partially destroyed, exposing Central Dogma.
We can't even estimate how much money and time have been lost.
This is because we didn't put a bell around Ikari's neck.
A bell was there, but it didn't ring.
A bell that doesn't ring has no purpose.
We'll make sure the bell works next time.
My, my.
What a completely unexpected situation.
How will you explain this to the committee?
I mean, to Sele?
There isn't anything to explain.
Unit 1 wasn't under our control.
This was an accident.
Thus, Unit 1 will remain frozen until the committee gives us further orders.
Exactly.
That is a very appropriate decision.
However, isn't your son still trapped inside it?
I knew this was hopeless.
It's not accepting the eject code.
What about the backup codes?
Also refused.
Even a direct circuit isn't getting through.
But the plug's video monitor's still active.
I'm channeling it to the main screen.
What in the hell is this?
This is the truth behind a 400% sync ratio.
I can't believe it.
What happened to Shinji?
He's been taken into Ava Unit 1.
Taken into it?
What in the hell is an Ava?
It's a thing created by man in man's own image.
I really can't describe it any other way.
Created by man?
You didn't create anything.
You just copied something you found in the Antarctic.
What was the original?
That's what I want to know.
This is not just a copy.
A human will is inside it.
Are you saying somebody willed this to happen?
Yes.
The Ava did.
Do something, damn it!
You created this, didn't you?
Take responsibility for what you've done!
In regard to the issue of the Nansa Islands, the government and the Ministry of Internal Affairs have officially announced that there is no federal involvement.
It has been a month since the terrorist incident in Tokyo, too, and the government has...
I'm still alive.
I know that Wonder Girl's still alive!
Don't bother me with trivial crap like that, Misato!
I can't believe it.
I couldn't do anything.
I can't believe that stupid Shinji outperformed me.
I can't stand it!
What do you mean you're going to salvage Shinji?
Well, theoretically, Shinji's life force still exists in there.
Ha!
And will you be respecting that life this time?
Losing Shinji is out of the question now.
Oh, I don't know.
What Nerve wants is Unit 1 as their tool, not Shinji.
I don't deny it.
Our assumption is that Shinji's body lost its ego border, and that he's now floating in the entry plug in quantum form.
You're saying that Shinji has shifted into a form we can't see?
Yes.
The LCL has chemically altered into something very similar to the seawater of primitive Earth.
In fact, it's almost identical to the primordial soup we've duplicated in laboratories.
Primordial soup?
Yes.
All of the substances which composed Shinji are still preserved in the plug, and his soul exists there as well.
In fact, his ego image is giving a sort of substance to his plug suit.
In other words, this salvage operation must both reconstruct his body and return his soul into it.
Is that possible?
Possible? With the Magi's support? Yes, it is.
This is all theoretical stuff you're talking about, isn't it?
You won't know what will really happen until you do it.
What is this?
Where am I?
The entry plug of Unit 1?
But there's nobody here.
Not even myself.
What is this?
I don't understand.
These people.
Yes, they're people I know.
People who know me.
I understand now.
This is my world.
What is this?
This is supposed to be my world, but this I don't understand.
An image from outside.
A hostile image.
That's right.
The enemy.
Enemy.
Our enemies are something called angels.
They have the names of the angels too.
They are the targets of Eva and Nerve.
This is our revenge for the death of Misaro's father.
But why do I fight?
Why do I do this despite all the pain and suffering?
What are you, stupid?
An unknown enemy is attacking us.
Of course we have to fight them.
Who cares what they think?
Am I odd to try to find a reason to fight?
Am I not supposed to think about it?
Enemy.
All are my enemies.
That which threatens us is the enemy.
Of course, how can I be faulted for protecting my own life and those of others?
Enemy.
Oh wow.
Damn it!
God damn it!
You hurt Doji and killed my mother!
FATHER!
Do you hate your father?
Anyone would hate him. He's no father at all.
You don't understand him, do you?
Of course not. In 14 years, I've hardly ever even seen him.
Is that why you hate him?
Yes. My father doesn't need me. My father deserted me.
Am I a substitute?
Yes! That's got to be it! He abandoned me because he already had Ayanami.
As if you didn't already run away yourself.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up! It's all his fault!
That time I was actually going to tell him I hate him!
Did you make me become a pilot just to make me suffer?
Correct.
How can you say that? Why do you have to be so cold? It's not fair!
You didn't even need me, did you?
I called you because I had a use for you.
But why? Why is it me?
Because there is no one else who can do it.
No way. Why haven't I ever seen this before?
It's not fair! It's not possible!
Correct. Yeah, I know this to be true.
That's right! I already knew Ava!
I already knew Ava!
And then I ran away, leaving my father and mother behind!
Current concentration of LCL is stable at 36. Oxygen concentration is nominal.
Electromagnetic radiation pulse is normal. Wave pattern is zero.
All counters are functioning normally.
Salvage operation guidelines.
It's incredible that you were able to come up with all this in just one month.
Thanks for the credit, but this isn't all my work.
The majority of this data is from ten years ago.
What data from ten years ago? Has this happened before?
Yes, but it was before I started working here. It was during my mother's time.
But I can still pick her brains.
Then how did it come out ten years ago?
They didn't succeed.
Kindness.
Warmth.
Is this warmth part of being human?
I was never aware of it until now.
What is loneliness?
I was never aware of it before, but now I think I know what it is.
And what is happiness?
I didn't know what it was, but now I think I understand.
Are others kind to you?
Do you know?
They are.
And why?
Because.
Because I pilot an Ava.
That's why they treat me so well.
That's the reason I keep going on.
It's the justification for my continuing existence.
Who and why I am.
That's why I have to pilot the Ava.
Which means?
To fight.
I have to fight the ones that they call our enemy.
And that means?
That I have to win.
That's right.
I can't lose.
I must be the pilot.
I must do what they tell me to do.
And I've got to win.
Just like they tell me to.
Otherwise, I'm nobody.
Nobody.
No.
Work hard.
Work hard, Shinji.
You have to work, you stupid idiot.
Yeah, work hard.
You gotta work hard.
Good job, Shinji.
Misato.
Ritsuko.
Asuka.
Toji.
Kinsuke.
Father.
They all respect me.
They respect me when I pilot the Ava.
They respect this totally worthless being.
They all tell me piloted, so I'll prove to my father that I'm worth something.
Work hard, Shinji.
But I am working hard.
I am.
Somebody, please.
Somebody be nice to me.
I fought so much.
I'm doing the best I can.
Can you treat me better?
Can you be nice to me?
Why can't you be nice to me?
I'm nice to you.
Tell me, Shinji.
Do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It could be very, very nice.
Ask me anytime.
I'm ready.
Hey, Shinji, you idiot.
Don't you want to be one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It would be really awesome.
You ought to appreciate your good fortune.
Come on.
Ikari.
Do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body?
It could be very pleasant.
Shinji?
Do you want to become one with me?
To be of one mind and body and soul?
It could be very pleasant.
Relax and release your soul.
All of the probes have been inserted.
Electromagnetic radius is fixed at zero minus three.
Eagle water pulse connection is complete.
Roger, start the salvage operation.
Initiating program.
Transmitting first signal.
Signal received.
No rejection.
Proceed to send the second and third signals.
Subjects, kathesis is normal.
This turtle cannot be confirmed.
Affirmative.
Shift the subject to stage two.
Come on, Shinji.
Stupid Shinji.
Shinji Ikari.
Hey, Shinji.
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari.
Shinji.
Stupid Shinji.
Shinji Ikari.
Hey, Shinji.
Yo, Shinji.
Ikari.
Hey, Shinji.
Yo, Shinji.
Oh, Shinji.
It's no good.
His ego borderline is frozen into a fixed loop.
Try to radiate the wave patterns from all directions.
My God.
All of the radiated signals are being trapped in climb space.
What does that mean?
It means we failed.
Abort intervention.
Reverse the tangent graph.
Set the addition value at zero.
Rate.
Distudo reaction in the Q area.
Pattern is sepia.
I've got a change in the core pulse two.
Plus O3. Confirm.
Maintaining current condition as priority.
Stop that backflow.
Right. Plus .5.
Point 8.
This is all wrong.
I can't stop it.
What's going on?
Don't you want to come back?
Why, Shinji?
I don't...
I don't understand myself.
I...
What do I want?
What do you want?
What do you want, Shinji?
The EVA is rejecting the signal.
Shinji's ego formation is disintegrating in the LCL.
Pressure in the plug is increasing.
Abort all operations.
Power down.
It's not working.
The plug is being ejected.
Shinji!
Where am I?
Inside the EVA.
Inside the EVA?
Did I pilot the EVA again?
But why?
You won't pilot the EVA anymore?
I decided that I would never pilot EVA again.
But you have just piloted Evangelion Unit 1.
Shinji, you are here because you have piloted the EVA.
Piloting the EVA has created your present.
You can never deny your past, Shinji.
Nor can you deny the fact that you did indeed pilot it once more.
That which is, is.
It's true.
I just wanted to tell you that only you can decide.
It's your future.
Only you can decide, Shinji.
You must make a choice.
I...
What good is your goddamn science?
It can't even save one small life.
Give me back my Shinji.
Give him back!
That scent.
A human smell.
Misato?
Ayanami?
No, not that.
That's right.
This is the smell of my mother.
The second impact has occurred.
Must he live in this hell?
Anywhere can be heaven.
As long as you try to live.
And because he is alive,
for as long as he lives,
he will have a chance to attain happiness.
Of course.
You're right.
Mother?
Have you decided yet?
If it's a boy, Shinji.
If it's a girl,
I'll name the baby, Ray.
Hm.
Shinji.
Ray.
Good names.
Mother.
Shinji.
Shinji!
Well, Unit 1's restoration
ought to be finished
by the day after tomorrow.
So even when they're given
divine power,
human beings still
treat it as a matter of fact.
I can hardly agree with that.
Speaking of which,
the committee is looking
at freezing the Evas.
The Evangelion androids.
They may be man-made,
but who knows
what lurks inside
that black box.
Uh-huh.
I'm just glad
that Shinji's life
was saved.
No thanks to me.
The credit probably
goes to you.
Hey,
you want to go
bar hopping tonight?
Uh,
sorry.
I've got to go somewhere.
I'll sleep with you.
See ya!
Shinji's just been saved
and she's already
running to her lover?
Well,
I guess I can't blame her.
Ritsuko must be thinking
I'm pretty disgusting.
Appearing to give in
to our sexual desires
makes for a more
realistic appearance.
A good deception.
Deceive the Intelligence Department?
Or the Commander
in Ritsuko.
Or me.
No, no.
I meant myself.
You want to fool
the others?
You never show interest
in others,
but you want their attention.
You really are
just like my dad.
I didn't know
you still smoked.
I only smoke
after this sort of thing,
so nobody knows
but you.
Here's smoke
in your eyes.
Really?
I'm honored.
And how's
instrumentality going?
Adam could wipe out
mankind.
Why is he being
kept there?
Did you come to see me
just to learn that?
Yeah.
Well, actually,
that's one of the reasons.
It would be my honor
to be used
as my lady's cat's paw.
But I can't.
I just want you
to know
what I want.
What are Nerve
and Commander Ikari
really planning?
I'd like to know
that myself.
Hey,
you can't dodge
my questions
by doing that.
No,
don't put strange
things in there.
What are you
doing?
I can't believe
this.
What?
What is this?
This is for you.
The first time
in eight years.
And maybe
the last as well.
吉ney
plays
Thank you.